<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-05T21:02:09-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Webomage</title><subtitle>DevOps, Integration, AI/LLM, Fullstack, Mobile &amp; Compliance Engineering led by Aleksei Tcelishchev</subtitle><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><entry><title type="html">Zero Trust Ai Kubernetes</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/zero-trust-ai-kubernetes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zero Trust Ai Kubernetes" /><published>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/zero-trust-ai-kubernetes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/zero-trust-ai-kubernetes.html"><![CDATA[<hr />
<p>layout: post
title: Zero-Trust Blueprint for AI on Kubernetes
date: 2025-12-03
categories: [“news”]
tags: [“kubernetes”, “zero-trust”, “ai”, “security”, “devops”]
source_url: https://www.cncf.io/blog/2025/10/10/a-blueprint-for-zero-trust-ai-on-kubernetes/
image_prompt: Blueprint diagram of Kubernetes pods running AI workloads secured by zero-trust network policies, mTLS locks, and observability flows.
image_alt: Zero-trust security architecture for AI on Kubernetes.</p>

<p>AI workloads on Kubernetes amplify traditional risks like lateral movement, exposed endpoints, and credential leaks, with elevated stakes from sensitive training data and high-cost inference. Default Kubernetes networking permits unrestricted pod-to-pod communication, enabling a single compromise to propagate across clusters housing LLMs, feature stores, and inference gateways.</p>

<p>A CNCF blueprint applies zero-trust principles using established cloud-native tools: pod-level network policies via CNIs such as Calico or Cilium, secure ingress controllers, mTLS for service-to-service traffic, and identity-based access controls. This setup ensures only authorized flows reach critical AI components, mitigating unauthorized access to models and datasets.</p>

<p>For engineering leaders, implementing this blueprint means prioritizing network segmentation and observability—capturing logs, metrics, and traces to monitor AI traffic patterns and detect anomalies. DevOps and infra teams can leverage these practices to safeguard AI pipelines without custom solutions, balancing velocity with protection for production-scale deployments.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: Zero-Trust Blueprint for AI on Kubernetes date: 2025-12-03 categories: [“news”] tags: [“kubernetes”, “zero-trust”, “ai”, “security”, “devops”] source_url: https://www.cncf.io/blog/2025/10/10/a-blueprint-for-zero-trust-ai-on-kubernetes/ image_prompt: Blueprint diagram of Kubernetes pods running AI workloads secured by zero-trust network policies, mTLS locks, and observability flows. image_alt: Zero-trust security architecture for AI on Kubernetes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Top AI DevOps Tools for 2025</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/03/ai-devops-tools-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top AI DevOps Tools for 2025" /><published>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/03/ai-devops-tools-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/03/ai-devops-tools-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>AI integration in DevOps platforms is advancing predictive analytics, anomaly detection, incident response, code quality checks, and cloud cost optimization. Engineering leaders can leverage these tools to analyze telemetry and logs, forecasting outages, performance issues, and capacity needs proactively. This shifts teams from reactive firefighting to preventive infrastructure management.</p>

<p>Incident response benefits from AI-driven triage of alerts, action recommendations, and automated remediation for routine problems, reducing mean time to resolution. Code-focused AI identifies bugs, vulnerabilities, and style issues early in CI/CD pipelines, while cloud tools optimize resource sizing, eliminate waste, and refine autoscaling policies. For infra teams, this means measurable reductions in downtime and operational costs.</p>

<p>The 2025 landscape includes IaC platforms like Spacelift, security scanners such as Snyk, observability solutions from Datadog and Dynatrace, incident tools like incident.io and PagerDuty, and coding assistants including GitHub Copilot and Amazon Q Developer. DevOps leaders should evaluate these for integration into existing stacks to enhance reliability and efficiency without overhauling processes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="AI" /><category term="DevOps" /><category term="tools" /><category term="IaC" /><category term="observability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI integration in DevOps platforms is advancing predictive analytics, anomaly detection, incident response, code quality checks, and cloud cost optimization. Engineering leaders can leverage these tools to analyze telemetry and logs, forecasting outages, performance issues, and capacity needs proactively. This shifts teams from reactive firefighting to preventive infrastructure management.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Azure Support Cert Updates</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/azure-support-cert-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Azure Support Cert Updates" /><published>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/azure-support-cert-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/12/03/azure-support-cert-updates.html"><![CDATA[<hr />
<p>layout: post
title: Microsoft Retires Niche Azure Certifications for Broader Role-Based Paths
date: 2025-12-03
categories: [“news”]
tags: [“azure”, “certifications”, “microsoft”, “devops”]
source_url: https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/blog/skills-hub-blog/announcing-updates-to-azure-and-support-engineer-training-and-certification-port/3719266
image_prompt: Illustration of a certification roadmap shifting from narrow Azure icons like IoT and Teams to broader cloud admin and networking paths on a hybrid cloud background.
image_alt: Azure certification evolution from niche to role-based certifications.</p>

<p>Microsoft is retiring several niche Azure and support engineer certifications effective July 31, 2023, including Azure Stack Hub Operator, Azure IoT Developer, Azure Support Engineer for Connectivity, Exchange Online Support Engineer, and Teams Support Engineer. This move aligns training with real-world responsibilities by emphasizing broader, role-based certifications that better support hybrid and multi-cloud environments.</p>

<p>Engineering leaders should guide teams toward recommended alternatives: Azure Administrator Associate and Windows Server Hybrid Administrator Associate for hybrid operations; Azure Network Engineer Associate and Azure Administrator Associate for networking and connectivity; and Messaging Administrator Associate or the new Collaboration Communications Systems Engineer for messaging and collaboration support. Existing certification holders retain their credentials on transcripts and have a final renewal window.</p>

<p>For DevOps and infrastructure teams, this shift reduces fragmentation in skill validation, enabling focus on comprehensive competencies essential for managing Azure workloads at scale. Webomage recommends reviewing Microsoft Learn paths and practice assessments to map current skills to these updated certifications, ensuring alignment with evolving infra demands.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[layout: post title: Microsoft Retires Niche Azure Certifications for Broader Role-Based Paths date: 2025-12-03 categories: [“news”] tags: [“azure”, “certifications”, “microsoft”, “devops”] source_url: https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/blog/skills-hub-blog/announcing-updates-to-azure-and-support-engineer-training-and-certification-port/3719266 image_prompt: Illustration of a certification roadmap shifting from narrow Azure icons like IoT and Teams to broader cloud admin and networking paths on a hybrid cloud background. image_alt: Azure certification evolution from niche to role-based certifications.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KubeCon NA 2025: AI Sparks a Platform Engineering Revival</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubecon-platform-engineering-revival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KubeCon NA 2025: AI Sparks a Platform Engineering Revival" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubecon-platform-engineering-revival</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubecon-platform-engineering-revival.html"><![CDATA[<p>Reports from KubeCon North America 2025 highlight a clear theme: AI is <strong>reviving and reshaping platform engineering</strong>, not replacing it. The Kubernetes ecosystem has exploded from a handful of projects to a dense landscape of tools, and the arrival of strong open-source LLMs (such as the widely discussed DeepSeek moment) reinforces that there will never be a single “universal” platform. Instead, organisations are rediscovering the need to treat internal platforms as products with real users – their developers.</p>

<p>Speakers at the event emphasised that good platforms hide complexity without pretending it doesn’t exist. Developers want simple abstractions when they’re shipping features on “day one,” but operators still need precise control on “day two” when debugging, scaling, or patching real systems. New open-source work like Formæ, an IaC abstraction layer that unifies infrastructure changes into stateful elements, reflects this direction: let developers build declaratively, while giving operators a safe way to make targeted changes without fighting Terraform in every incident.</p>

<p>Hiring trends echo this shift. Companies such as LinkedIn report that engineers who actively contribute to Kubernetes and related open-source projects tend to be productive much faster when they join platform teams. Open-source experience turns out to be a strong proxy for the mindset and skills needed to evolve complex, AI-augmented platforms. For teams building or refactoring internal platforms today, the message from KubeCon is straightforward: invest in platform engineering as a discipline, not just in a pile of tools, and expect AI to amplify that practice rather than eliminate it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="kubernetes" /><category term="platform-engineering" /><category term="ai" /><category term="devops" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reports from KubeCon North America 2025 highlight a clear theme: AI is reviving and reshaping platform engineering, not replacing it. The Kubernetes ecosystem has exploded from a handful of projects to a dense landscape of tools, and the arrival of strong open-source LLMs (such as the widely discussed DeepSeek moment) reinforces that there will never be a single “universal” platform. Instead, organisations are rediscovering the need to treat internal platforms as products with real users – their developers.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/kubecon-platform-engineering-revival.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/kubecon-platform-engineering-revival.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kubernetes Trends 2025: Serverless K8s, AI/ML Workloads, WASM, and Zero Trust</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubernetes-trends-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kubernetes Trends 2025: Serverless K8s, AI/ML Workloads, WASM, and Zero Trust" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubernetes-trends-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/kubernetes-trends-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recent Kubernetes trend write-ups for 2025 paint a picture of a platform that’s both maturing and expanding in scope. One thread is <strong>serverless Kubernetes</strong>: using tools like Knative, OpenFaaS, or OpenWhisk to hide most of the cluster management details and expose a pay-as-you-go, function-style interface. This makes K8s more attractive to smaller teams and bursty, compute-heavy workloads such as inference serving or batch simulations.</p>

<p>Another big area is <strong>AI/ML on Kubernetes</strong>. Teams are increasingly running training and inference pipelines directly on clusters, taking advantage of Kubernetes’ scheduling and resource management. Tooling such as Kubeflow and TensorFlow-on-Kubernetes helps orchestrate data ingestion, training jobs, and model serving. That’s particularly relevant for sectors like finance, healthcare, and e‑commerce, where workloads are both data-intensive and latency-sensitive.</p>

<p>The ecosystem is also experimenting with <strong>WebAssembly (WASM)</strong> for lighter-weight, faster-starting workloads and tightening security with <strong>zero trust</strong> approaches. Projects like SpinKube aim to make WASM workloads first-class citizens in Kubernetes, which could reshape how some serverless functions and microservices are packaged. On the security side, service meshes and strict identity-based access are becoming the default way to achieve zero trust for pod-to-pod communication. For platform teams, the trend is clear: clusters are becoming the substrate for a wider mix of workloads and trust models, not just “plain” containerised web services.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="kubernetes" /><category term="serverless" /><category term="ai" /><category term="wasm" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent Kubernetes trend write-ups for 2025 paint a picture of a platform that’s both maturing and expanding in scope. One thread is serverless Kubernetes: using tools like Knative, OpenFaaS, or OpenWhisk to hide most of the cluster management details and expose a pay-as-you-go, function-style interface. This makes K8s more attractive to smaller teams and bursty, compute-heavy workloads such as inference serving or batch simulations.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/kubernetes-trends-2025.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/kubernetes-trends-2025.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Edge AI in Cochlear Implants: Decision Trees, Power Budgets, and Upgradeable Firmware</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/edge-ai-cochlear-implants.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Edge AI in Cochlear Implants: Decision Trees, Power Budgets, and Upgradeable Firmware" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/edge-ai-cochlear-implants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/edge-ai-cochlear-implants.html"><![CDATA[<p>A recent deep dive into Cochlear’s Nucleus Nexa System shows what <strong>edge AI</strong> looks like when it has to live inside the human body for decades. The system uses an environmental classifier called SCAN 2 to categorise sound as speech, speech-in-noise, music, noise, or quiet. A decision tree model then maps these classifications to sound processing strategies, adjusting the electrical signals sent to the implant in real time.</p>

<p>What makes this example stand out is the combination of machine learning with extreme power constraints. The implant and external sound processor share intelligence via a low-power RF link, using Dynamic Power Management to keep the device operational over a 40+ year lifespan. On top of that, spatial processing features like ForwardFocus automatically reduce background noise using dual microphones, without adding extra decision-making burden on the wearer.</p>

<p>The other breakthrough is <strong>upgradeability</strong>. Historically, once an implant was in place, its internal technology was effectively frozen. With the Nucleus Nexa implant, firmware updates can now be pushed into the device itself, not just into the external hardware, while still relying on close-range, carefully controlled update channels. Cochlear is using this to store a user’s personalised hearing map directly on the implant and is exploring future upgrades toward deep neural network models and remote monitoring. It’s a preview of where regulated edge AI is headed: tiny, power-aware models, robust safety constraints, and long-term software life cycles.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="ai" /><category term="edge" /><category term="healthcare" /><category term="devices" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent deep dive into Cochlear’s Nucleus Nexa System shows what edge AI looks like when it has to live inside the human body for decades. The system uses an environmental classifier called SCAN 2 to categorise sound as speech, speech-in-noise, music, noise, or quiet. A decision tree model then maps these classifications to sound processing strategies, adjusting the electrical signals sent to the implant in real time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/edge-ai-cochlear-implants.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/edge-ai-cochlear-implants.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">EU AI Cloud: SAP’s Take on European AI &amp;amp; Cloud Sovereignty</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/eu-ai-cloud-sovereignty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EU AI Cloud: SAP’s Take on European AI &amp;amp; Cloud Sovereignty" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/eu-ai-cloud-sovereignty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/eu-ai-cloud-sovereignty.html"><![CDATA[<p>SAP’s new EU AI Cloud approach is an example of how seriously large vendors are taking <strong>AI sovereignty</strong> in Europe. Working with partners such as Cohere, SAP is packaging agent-style and multimodal AI models so that customers with strict data residency requirements can still adopt modern AI. These capabilities are exposed through SAP Business Technology Platform, giving enterprises more control over performance and where workloads actually run.</p>

<p>A key theme is deployment choice. EU AI Cloud is built on top of SAP Sovereign Cloud, which lets customers pick different levels of control. Some will run on SAP’s own infrastructure in European data centers; others may use a sovereign on-site model where SAP manages the stack inside the customer’s facilities. There are also options for mixing this with selected hyperscalers or region-specific offerings like Delos Cloud in Germany. The common thread is keeping operational control and data locality aligned with European regulatory expectations.</p>

<p>For teams building AI-heavy systems, this highlights a broader pattern: architecture and vendor choices now have to account for data jurisdiction as a first-class constraint. Sovereign cloud offerings won’t replace mainstream public cloud, but they are becoming an important tool for organisations operating under EU privacy, retention and access rules — especially those in the public sector, healthcare, and finance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="ai" /><category term="cloud" /><category term="sovereignty" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SAP’s new EU AI Cloud approach is an example of how seriously large vendors are taking AI sovereignty in Europe. Working with partners such as Cohere, SAP is packaging agent-style and multimodal AI models so that customers with strict data residency requirements can still adopt modern AI. These capabilities are exposed through SAP Business Technology Platform, giving enterprises more control over performance and where workloads actually run.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/eu-ai-cloud-sovereignty.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/eu-ai-cloud-sovereignty.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Generative AI in 2025: Cheaper LLMs, Agentic Workflows, and the Data Wall</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/generative-ai-trends-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generative AI in 2025: Cheaper LLMs, Agentic Workflows, and the Data Wall" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/generative-ai-trends-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/generative-ai-trends-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2025, large language models are no longer exotic, ultra-expensive toys. The cost of a single LLM response has dropped by orders of magnitude and is now comparable to a basic web search, making real-time AI far more practical in day-to-day business workflows. New generations of models such as Claude Sonnet 4, Gemini Flash 2.5, Grok 4 and DeepSeek V3 focus less on raw size and more on latency, reasoning quality, and how well they integrate with real systems.</p>

<p>This maturing wave is also treating hallucination as an engineering problem instead of an unfortunate quirk. Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) – where models ground answers in search results or private data – is now standard, and new benchmarks like RGB and RAGTruth are being used to measure when models drift from the facts. At the same time, adoption is shifting from simple content generation toward <strong>agentic AI</strong>, where models can trigger workflows, call tools and APIs, and operate as semi-autonomous agents inside digital ecosystems.</p>

<p>A second bottleneck is data. Scraping the open web is no longer enough to fuel larger and larger models, and licensing constraints are getting stricter. That is pushing synthetic data from a research experiment into a strategic capability. Work such as Microsoft’s SynthLLM suggests that, when used carefully, synthetic datasets can be tuned for predictable performance and even reduce overall data requirements for stronger models. For enterprises, the emerging playbook is clear: combine smaller, better-grounded models with strong retrieval and carefully curated (or synthetic) data instead of simply chasing parameter counts.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="ai" /><category term="llm" /><category term="enterprise" /><category term="rag" /><category term="synthetic-data" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2025, large language models are no longer exotic, ultra-expensive toys. The cost of a single LLM response has dropped by orders of magnitude and is now comparable to a basic web search, making real-time AI far more practical in day-to-day business workflows. New generations of models such as Claude Sonnet 4, Gemini Flash 2.5, Grok 4 and DeepSeek V3 focus less on raw size and more on latency, reasoning quality, and how well they integrate with real systems.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/generative-ai-trends-2025.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/generative-ai-trends-2025.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI Trends in DevOps 2025: Agents, Open Models, and New Architectures</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/ai-trends-devops-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Trends in DevOps 2025: Agents, Open Models, and New Architectures" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/ai-trends-devops-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/news/2025/12/02/ai-trends-devops-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>AI in DevOps is moving beyond simple copilots toward <strong>agentic workflows</strong>. Modern agents can reflect on their own actions, call APIs, plan multi-step tasks, and collaborate with other agents – not just autocomplete commands. Teams are already using these capabilities in production tools: AI-driven task management, documentation flows, and even financial operations that orchestrate work across systems. The key for DevOps leaders is to decide which workflows are safe to hand over to agents, define clear error budgets and interaction rules, and keep evaluation loops in place so agents don’t quietly drift.</p>

<p>At the same time, the balance between closed and open-source LLMs is shifting. New open models such as DeepSeek R1 and specialised tools like Mistral OCR are reducing the gap with proprietary offerings while bringing better cost control and customisation options. However, “open-source” remains a fuzzy label – licenses, datasets and access patterns vary widely – so due diligence is becoming part of standard platform work. Teams need to match models to use cases based on cost, latency, and governance requirements, and update those choices as the landscape changes.</p>

<p>Under the hood, research is also challenging the dominance of vanilla transformers. Hybrid approaches that mix transformers with newer architectures such as Mamba or linear-recurrence layers are promising faster inference and better resource usage. For DevOps and platform engineers, this doesn’t mean rewriting everything, but it does mean planning for more diversity in model architectures and hardware. Platform stacks that can host a mix of models – closed and open, transformer and hybrid – will be in a stronger position than those optimised for a single vendor or approach.</p>]]></content><author><name>Aleksei Tcelishchev</name></author><category term="news" /><category term="ai" /><category term="devops" /><category term="agents" /><category term="llm" /><category term="architecture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI in DevOps is moving beyond simple copilots toward agentic workflows. Modern agents can reflect on their own actions, call APIs, plan multi-step tasks, and collaborate with other agents – not just autocomplete commands. Teams are already using these capabilities in production tools: AI-driven task management, documentation flows, and even financial operations that orchestrate work across systems. The key for DevOps leaders is to decide which workflows are safe to hand over to agents, define clear error budgets and interaction rules, and keep evaluation loops in place so agents don’t quietly drift.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/ai-trends-devops-2025.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://0.0.0.0:4000/assets/news/ai-trends-devops-2025.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>